History is about to change
Colette is a drama, history film directed by Wash Westmoreland.
After marrying a successful Parisian writer known commonly as Willy, Sidonie-Gabrielle Colette is transplanted
from her childhood home in rural France to the intellectual and artistic splendor of Paris.
Soon after, Willy convinces Colette to ghostwrite for him.
She pens a semi-autobiographical novel about a witty and brazen country girl
named Claudine, sparking a bestseller and a cultural sensation.
After its success, Colette and Willy become the talk of Paris and
their adventures inspire additional Claudine novels.
Colette, played by Keira Knightley.
Willy, played by Dominic West.
Missy, played by Denise Gough.
Sido, played by Fiona Shaw.
Jules, played by Robert Pugh.
Georgie Raoul-Duval, played by Eleanor Tomlinson.
Colette is a 2018 biographical drama film directed by Wash Westmoreland, from a screenplay by Westmoreland,
Rebecca Lenkiewicz and Richard Glatzer, based upon the life of the French novelist Colette.
It stars Keira Knightley, Dominic West, Eleanor Tomlinson, and Denise Gough.
It had its world premiere at the Sundance Film Festival on January 20, 2018.
It was released in the United States on September 21,
2018, by Bleecker Street and 30West.
The film premiered in London at the BFI London Film Festival and was
released in the United Kingdom on January 11, 2019, by Lionsgate.
The film explores themes of paris, france, nobel
prize, biography, author, 19th century.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.